字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧、日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译:  火车站长赛太公    火车美人小兔美
翻译:  Eunice    洗七里
校对:  赛太公欢庆火车站一周年
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第十一集
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
我让人帮您把这放到礼物桌吧
Can I have that dropped at the gift table for you?
我自己拿着就好  这份礼物很特别
Ah, I think I'll hang onto this. This is a special gift.
是个恒温酒柜  有36个瓶位  不锈钢制
It's a wine fridge -- 36 bottles, stainless steel,
有双温区  可分别存放白酒和红酒
dual temp zones for your whites, your reds.
她不在乎  刚才那个神父也一样
She doesn't care. Okay. And neither did the priest.
名为"帅炸了"的神父
Father O'GodHe'sHot.
可不是吗  他的唇多性感啊
I know. Those lips, right?
-这样说神父合适吗  -合适吗
- Is that appropriate? - Appropriate?
你也从来没骄傲地抱着我们
You never carried us around as proudly
像你现在抱着那玩意儿一样
as you're carrying around that thing.
30年前  我没有免费帮你贝姬姑妈做衣柜
30 years ago, I didn't do your Aunt Becky's closets for free.
全家的人都说我是小气鬼
The whole family got together and decided I was cheap --
叫我"铁公鸡"
called me "High Pockets."
我们就来看看她儿子布莱恩
Well, we'll see what her boy Brian says
收到这个被时尚杂志评为
when he opens what Esquire Magazine called
"再也不需换新的恒温酒柜"时  会怎么说
"The last under-counter wine fridge you'll ever need."
铁公鸡
High Pockets.
我们直接到吧台去吧
Can we just find the bar?
我如果说不去  是不是会超好笑
How funny would it be if I said no?
我勒个...妈
Mother of...us.
妈  她怎么会在这儿
Mom! What is she doing here?
她跟这些人都没亲戚关系啊
She's not even related to these people!
天啊
Oh, my God.
只有你  我和爸妈
You, me, Mom, Dad, alone.
没有歌洛莉亚在这帮忙吸收仇恨的能量
Without Gloria to absorb the hate.
我怎么慌了  我好慌啊
Okay, why am I scared? I'm feeling scared.
因为你正回想起过去的每一次家族聚会
Because you are flashing back to every family event
最后都是爸爸用气音吼妈妈说
that ended with Dad whisper-screaming at Mom,
"你冷静点"  而她都会狂甩手拿包
"Would you calm down?" while she would swing her pocketbook
直到包包像墨西哥陶罐一样爆开  掉出一堆药丸
around until it burst open like a pill-packed pinata.
天啊  我不想再当闹笑话的那家人
Oh, God. I-I don't want to be the make-a-scene family. Again.
爸爸在他们为酒柜颁发个英雄奖给他之前
Well, Dad's not leaving until they award him CNN Hero
是不会走的
for bringing the wine fridge,
所以我们要不各领走一个家长
so maybe we just each take a parent
尽量不让他们碰到面
and try and keep them apart as much as possible?
这是我们最可能平安度过今日的方法了
Probably our best shot at an uneventful day.
但我们能不能别争让对方去陪着...
But can we please not fight over who has to care of --
妈
Mom!
米奇尔
Mitchell!
你好
Hi.
见到你真开心  宝贝儿
Oh, it's so good to see you, honey.
我找来一份校园地图  你看看
Hey. I got us a campus map, and look at this --
里面有一章特别介绍我以前大学兄弟会呢
My old college frat has a chapter here!
根据继承权力  我有权
By legacy rights, I'm entitled
使用主层的洗手间和登记借走飞盘
to use the main-floor bathroom and sign out a frisbee.
酷
Cool.
你用这带子健身得挺猛啊
Wow, you're really giving those bands a workout.
想释放一些紧张情绪
Oh, just burning off some nervous energy.
他们不会在参观大学途中问问题吧
They don't ask questions on a college tour, right?
卢克  我  歌洛莉亚和曼尼要去参观大学
Luke and I, Gloria, and Manny are going on a college tour!
是曼尼的保底大学  对卢克来说则是机会渺茫
Safety school for Manny, long shot for Luke,
这很伤他自尊心
which hasn't been great for his self-esteem.
幸好  作为曾经的拉拉队队员
Luckily, as a former cheerleader,
我还记得怎样鼓舞士气
I haven't lost my gift for lifting spirits.
虽然我的身体已经不再柔软  摆不出N字了
Though I can no longer make an N with my body.
这样健身挺有效的
This is a great workout.
不
Ow! No!
抱歉  抱歉  你们快来看
Sorry, sorry! Guys, come look!
我做了顽皮的坏事
I did something very bad.
曼尼在睡午觉
Manny is taking a nap,
我就把小猪放到床上去了
so I put a pig-a-let in the bed!
天啊
Oh, my God.
你从哪里弄来的
Where'd you get that?
你还记得我们遇到的那些农民吗
You remember those farmers that we met?
你想象不出他们为了一点小钱愿意做出什么事
You'll be surprised what they'll do for a couple of big tips.
你听到什么了
What did you hear?
要死了  什么鬼啊
Aah! Whoa! What is that?!
是只小猪
It's a pig-a-let!
你真该看看自己的表情
Man, you should see your face!
它还舔了我的脸  你干啥啊
Ohh, it licked my face! Why would you do this?
曼尼  别那么神经紧绷
Aye, Manny, don't be so uptight!
我在帮你备战大学生活
I'm preparing you for college
到时你就可以融入大家  交上朋友了
so that you fit in and make some friends.
两部电影皆描述了有关大学兄弟会的故事
我从电影《动物屋》里学来的招数
I took the idea from watching "The Animal House,"
还有《单身男子俱乐部》
"The Old School" Movie...
上大学是为了接受高等教育  不是恶作剧整人
College is about higher education, not pranks.
书呆
Nerd!
-她在那儿呢  -美女
- There she is! - Hey, lady.
我不能给你们免单
Yeah, I can't give you free stuff.
-我们走吧  -好  保重
- Let's go. - Okay, take care.
等等  等等  等等
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
天啊  是她
Oh, my gosh. It's her.
谁啊
Who?
坐在那边  外套美鞋子赞的金发女
The blonde over there in the cute jacket and fab shoes.
如果真是我想的那个人  我们超讨厌她
If that's who I think it is, we hate her so hard.
昨晚我被打劫了  没错
Last night, I was robbed. That's right.
我去看莉莉的舞蹈演出
There I was at Lily's dance recital,
屏住呼吸期待
breathlessly anticipating
我宝贝女儿的首次芭蕾独舞
my baby's first-ever ballet solo.
马上到了
Okay, here it comes.
为了这一刻  花掉的两千块舞蹈课钱都值了
This moment is worth every cent of the $2,000 in lessons.
啥
What?
天啊  我看不到了
Oh, my gosh. I can't see.
不是说了不许拍摄吗
Didn't they say no filming?
不好意思  女士
Excuse me. Miss?
你看到她多过分吗
Did you just see that?
那个可怕的女人劫走了我
That horrid woman robbed me
当骄傲爸爸的珍贵时刻
of my proud daddy moment
害我得向女儿说谎
and forced me to lie to my daughter.
"你跳得太棒了  莉莉"  可是是真的吗
"You danced beautifully, Lily!" But did she?
我咋知道啊
I have no idea!
你昨晚怎么不把她击倒啊
Why didn't you smack her down last night?
我是指用语言击倒
With words, obviously.
等等  男同可以扁女人吗
Wait, can gays smack women?
不行
No.
不行  你知道吗
No! You know what,
我昨晚本来要大骂她的
I would have cussed her out last night,
可那自私的老巫婆在她女儿一跳完
except the selfish hag left the moment
就溜走了
her daughter's dance was over.
希望这餐厅不禁止暴乱
I hope there's no rule in here about causing a commotion.
我们是觉得不需要
I mean, we didn't really feel the need
特地竖个牌子写明不可以  毕竟是文明社会了
to put it up on a sign because, you know, civilization.
我遵从的是老天爷的法律
Well, I answer to a higher law.
给我回来
Hey! Get back here!
你都不确定是不是她
You don't even know it's her.
你凭黑暗里看到的一个后脑勺
You're basing this off of the back of the head
就认定这是她
of someone you saw in the dark.
或许你能从"背后"认出前男友  但...
That may be how you recognize your old boyfriends, but...
不好意思
Excuse me.
虽然我很欣赏你的招数  并打算不给你功劳
As much as I admire that and do intend on using it
就让米奇尔来试这招  但做人要有底线
on Mitchell without giving you any credit, there is a line.
妈  我都不知道你要来
So, Mom, I didn't know that you would be, uh, be here.
我本来也没打算来
Oh, well, I wasn't planning on it --
离婚后都没见过这些人了
I haven't seen these people since the divorce --
但我新老公要去工作
Yeah. But then my new hubby had to work,
我于是心想  "写个新故事吧  迪迪"
and I thought -- "Write a new story, Dede."
就是啊
Yeah!
你一个人来的吗  还是...
So, are you here alone, or...?
你好美啊  这条裙子真漂亮
You look great! This dress is beautiful!
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
我从买来的车子的后尾箱里捡的
I found it in the trunk of a car I bought.
稍等  妈妈
Oh. One second, Mom.
是小卡
Oh, this is Cam texting.
是一个人的后脑勺的照片
The picture of the back of someone's head
还写着  "是她吗"
and the words, "Is this her?"
不知道你在说什么
No idea what you are talking about.
亲亲表情
Kissy face.
不好意思  能帮我们照张相吗
Excuse me. Can we get a pic?
宝贝儿来
Honey!
爸  你真有心
Dad, that's sweet.
不是吧
Really?
如果我和礼物分开了  还有证据
If we get separated, there's a record.
天啊
Oh, God.
别生气
Hey, don't be mad.
你不是吧
Are you kidding?
她消失了  好吗
She vanished, okay?
她做的那些鞋子走路没声音的
Those shoes she makes are soundless.
你们在这儿啊
Oh, there you are!
好啊
Okay.
这不是我的第一任家庭吗
if it isn't my first family.
真没想到你也会来
What a surprise, huh?
是啊  我想布莱恩邀请我
Yeah! I guess Brian invited me
是因为那个夏天我们收留过他
because of that summer we took him in.
还记得你偷偷试穿布莱恩的内裤被我抓到吗
Remember when I caught you trying on Brian's underpants?
不记得  你在说什么  妈
No, what even -- Mom!
这桌只有四个人吗
Oh, is it just the four of us?
是的
Yeah!
是的  你的座位在哪  妈
Yes, and where are you sitting, Mom?
让我送你回你那桌吧
I can walk you back to your table.
再等一会儿
In a minute.
我想叙叙旧
I'd like to visit a little.
我那桌的人我一个都不认识
I don't even know anyone at my table.
既然歌洛莉亚今天没来
Well, Gloria's not here...
谢谢你  杰
Oh, thank you, Jay.
让我帮你腾个位置
Here. Let me, uh...
这样真好
Well, this is fun.
-老队伍又会合了  -是啊
- The band's back together. - Yeah.
有人想来杯香槟吗
Would anyone care for some champagne?
-想  -我想来一杯
- Oh, yeah. - I'd love some.
-你猜对了  -谢谢
- Oh, you bet. Yeah. - Thank you.
一整盘都留下吧
I'll just take the tray.
入学越来越困难了
Admission has gotten tougher.
10位申请者中大约只有4位能入学
Only about 4 out of 10 applicants get accepted.
比那更低的几率你都克服过
You've beaten worse odds than that.
我们直到你6岁才想起给你接种疫苗
We forgot to get you vaccinated till you were 6.
本大学有许多引以为傲的毕业生
The University boasts many noted graduates --
科研人员  新闻工作者
research scientists, journalists,
还有一位挺出名的剧作家
and one pretty well-known playwright.
什么叫"挺出名"
Wow. "Pretty well-known?"
"著名的阿摩司"牌饼干
Imagine how many cookies
如果当初叫"挺出名的阿摩司"饼干
they could have sold if they called them
卖得出去才怪
"Pretty Well-Known Amos's."
我把你两只脚的鞋带绑在一起了
I tied your shoelaces together.
妈  你这几天是怎么了
Mom, what's going on with you?
我在帮你做心理准备
I am preparing you.
如果你不能自嘲
If you can't laugh at yourself,
就会成为被人嘲笑的目标
then you'll become a target.
大学可疯狂了  哥们
College crazy time, man!
打扰一下  史黛菲
Excuse me, Steffi?
我儿子蒂姆开发了一个金融应用程序
My son Tim here developed a finance app
摩根大通公司的人很感兴趣
that caught the eye of some folks at JP Morgan,
所以他得一边上学一边继续开发
so he'll need to keep that going along with school.
没问题
No problem.
许多学生在校时都有工作
Many students work while taking class.
-打扰一下  史黛菲  -你干什么
- Excuse me, Steffi? - What are you doing?
我儿子卢卡斯是经认证的业余蹦床运动员
My son Lucas here is a recognized amateur trampolinist.
爸
Dad!
我想你们应该有相应的训练设施
I'm assuming you guys have a training facility
让他能继续追求这门应用跳跃的艺术吧
so he can continue his pursuits in the applied bouncing arts?
我好像没听懂
I'm not sure I'm understanding...
你们有没有蹦床
Do you guys have a trampoline?
托儿所好像有张小的
I think there's a small one in the daycare center.
世上没有不够大的蹦床  只有...
There are no small trampolines, only --
我们还是继续吧
You know what? We can move on.
大家这边走
Everybody, this way!
你就直接问她昨晚有没有去看舞蹈演出
Just go ask her if she was at the recital,
如果她说有  就把她骂跑
and then tell her off if she says yes.
不行  我不能问  因为如果是她
No, I can't, because if it's her,
她会感觉到敌意然后否认
she'll sense confrontation coming and deny it.
我转到攻击模式时总能被人看出来
People can always tell when I'm in attack mode.
-因为你气得鼻孔扩大吗  -不是
- Mm, flared nostrils? - No.
因为你气得额头爆血管  脖子起红疹吗
Vein in your forehead? Blotchy neck?
不是  你们知道吗
No! You know what,
别怪我没提醒  你俩越来越像你们老妈了
and just a head's up, you both are turning into your mother.
好吧
Okay.
新计划
New plan.
你要干什么
What-What are you doing?
如果她平板电脑上有莉莉演出的视频
Well, if there's video of Lily's recital on her iPad,
我就能肯定是她
then I know it's for sure her,
再说我还能把视频发给自己
and plus, I can e-mail it to myself
再办个正式的观影派对
and have a proper viewing party.
我那天有事
Ooh, I've got a thing.
我八成要工作
Yeah, I'll probably be working.
我日子都还没定呢
I haven't even set a date yet.
好吧  要密码
Okay, there's a passcode.
当然要密码
Well, of course there's a passcode.
给我
Give me that.
好的  她点了撒糖粉的甜甜圈  所以
All right, well, she ordered a powdered doughnut, so...
果然
All right.
数字8  5  3和1上面都有带粉的指纹
Chalky fingerprints on the 8, the 5, the 3, and the 1.
密码是那4个数字的某种组合
Your passcode is some combination of those four.
我的天  你太天才了
Oh, my God. You're brilliant.
去年我还在加州理工学院做微分地形学
Last year, I was doing differential topography at Cal Tech,
如今却为老大不小还玩滑板的人
and now I sketch leaves in milk foam
在奶泡上画叶子
for adult skateboarders.
我需要找点别的追求
I need something more.
-她回来了  -什么
- She's coming back. - What?!
她回来了
She's coming back.
我把平板电脑留在桌上  被人偷走了
I left my iPad on the table, and somebody took it.
天哪  我没...
Oh, gosh! I didn't --
没什么  做好你的工作吗
Didn't what? Do your job?
你也没忙到不能...
It's not like you're so busy you don't have time to --
打扰一下  我不小心听到你们说话
Excuse me. I couldn't help overhearing.
你说的平板电脑是包里那个吗
Um, are you talking about that iPad in that bag there?
-天啊  -因为包里就有个平板电脑
- Oh, God. - 'Cause there's an iPad there.
我真是白痴
What a ditz.
我这次荒唐的相亲让我太紧张了
Ugh, I guess I'm just nervous for this stupid blind date
我真不该答应下来
I never should have agreed to.
糟糕
Oh, no.
你该不会就是理查德吧
You're not Richard, are you?
是的  我就是理查德
Uh, yes. I-I am Richard.
我是你的相亲对象
I'm your blind date.
你就是安娜吧
You're, uh, Ana.
我这人真是糟糕透顶  对吧
Oh! Am I the worst person ever?
相亲的目的不就是摸清你是个怎样的人吗
Well, that's what we're here to find out.
开玩笑的  快请坐
Kidding! Please sit!
我希望是她  她这人真恶心
I hope that is her. She's gross.
我想看他骂她
I want him to yell at her.
-是啊  -打扰一下
- Yeah. - Excuse me.
我是来相亲的
Um, I'm here for a blind date,
但我朋友没把对象的照片发给我
and my friend didn't even give me a picture.
我只知道那位女士的名字
I just know the woman's name.
你的顾客中有名叫安娜的吗
Any chance you served an Ana?
真是无巧不成书
Oh! Well, this is crazy.
安娜  快来见见
Ana, say hello to, uh...
-理查德  -正是
- Richard. - Yeah.
不好意思  我无意唐突
Um, sorry, I don't mean to be forward,
但你比瓦妮莎形容得美多了
but Vanessa kind of undersold how attractive you are.
太惊艳了
Wowza.
我因为被说漂亮而做过的无下限事太多了
The things I've done because people tell me I'm pretty,
差点会让人以为我其实不漂亮
you'd almost think I wasn't pretty.
1986年
So, 1986,
我们刚参加完我姐碧碧的婚礼回来
we were just coming back from my sister Bebe's wedding
那是我第一次梦到谋杀你
when I first had my dream about murdering you.
别说了  米奇尔有个有趣的故事
No! Mitchell has a funny story
不会揭开旧疮疤
that doesn't open old wounds
讲的是小卡在舞蹈演出的事
about Cam at a dance recital.
他当时气坏了  对吧  米奇尔
He got so mad, didn't he, Mitchell?
快告诉他们
Tell them!
是气坏了
So mad.
那不是86年  是87年
That wasn't '86. That was '87.
我们迟到是因为你逼我参加
The reason we were late was because of that damn
那个全美手拉手的破活动
Hands Across America that you made me do.
手拉手是在86年
Hands was '86,
你事后还感谢我了
and you thanked me afterwards
因为和你拉手的人
because you got to hold hands with someone
另一只手拉的是著名歌手威利·纳尔逊
that was holding hands with Willie Nelson.
那个活动是为什么筹善款来着  解决饥饿吗
What the hell was that whole thing about, anyway? Hunger?
在旧金山递给某人一个三明治
Hand somebody a sandwich in San Francisco
沿着人手传下去
and pass it down the line
一直传到波士顿某个流浪汉手里吗
till some bum gets ahold of it in Boston?
饥饿  是的  绝对是
Hunger, yeah. Definitely.
说起饥饿  米奇尔在节食呢
Um, Mitchell is on a diet, speaking of hunger.
你现在能吃什么
What can you eat now?
吃少点
Uh... less.
宝贝  我明白你的用意
Sweetie, I see what you're doing,
但你控制欲这么强  很难相处
but this whole controlling thing -- it's challenging.
在办公室很有帮助
Works good in the office,
但有时她比沙暴中的骆驼的屁股还紧绷
but sometimes she's as tight as a camel's ass in a sandstorm.
您这话略伤人吧
Ooh, this seems aggressive.
我想去
I'm just gonna --
能原谅我去用一下洗手间吗
May I be excused to go to the bathroom?
我也去  马上回来
Yeah. Me too. Be right back.
你别想跟我来这招
Hey! You do not get to do this.
不许你用你小时候
You do not get to shut down on me
对他们搞自闭的招数来对我
like you did when we were kids.
我才不要在这里帮你顶着压力
I am not gonna sit here taking the heat
而你却躲回房间大听女摇滚歌后的歌
while you go hide in your room blasting Pat Benatar.
我们到底为啥要坐在一起啊
Why are we even all sitting together?
我有个计划
This is my plan.
你得想出个理由
You're gonna come up with a reason
把妈带回她那桌
to take Mom back to her table.
可能你有一些基佬事儿想倾诉
Maybe you want to unload some gay stuff
而你又不想老爸听见
you don't want Dad to hear?
你人"真好"
You're lovely.
但我的梦境分析师帮我认识到
But my dream analyst helped me realize
其实我从未真的想要谋杀你
that I never wanted to murder you.
我想谋杀的是自己心中的愤怒
I wanted to murder the part of myself that was so angry.
你会愤怒是因为我情商低又爱吹牛逼
You were angry because I was an inconsiderate blow-hard.
别怪自己了
Oh, don't do that.
我们也有过许多欢乐时光啊  对吧  大人
We had plenty of good times, didn't we, Sarge?
当然啦  小豆宝
You bet we did, Pea.
这又是什么鬼
What fresh hell is this?
参观之旅就在地标钟楼下结束啦
We'll end our tour here at our iconic bell tower.
晚上的派对见啦
See you all at tonight's mixer!
我们回去前  想做点好玩的吗
Hey. Before we go back, you want to do something fun?
跟我来
Follow me.
-快看  -看个钟吗
- Check it out! -A bell?
不是单纯的钟
Not just a bell.
是一系列不同的钟组合成一种独特的乐器
A series of bells fed into an ingenious instrument
名为钟琴
known as a carillon.
想当年我也玩过这乐器
I monkied around with one back in the day.
一个叫葛雷琴的小妞带我上她钟楼
A cutie named Gretchen took me up to her belfry
亮了几招来让我"大开眼界"
and showed me some moves,
我现在意识到这话听起来有点黄
which I now realize sounds sexual.
还好啦  你说话常这样
Not really. You talk like this a lot.
重点是  葛雷琴靠着玩钟绝活
The point is, Gretchen got a full ride
得到了奖学金呢  好高啊
treading bells like these. Wow, that's high.
或许你也可以啊
Maybe you could, too.
让你去上个班...
Get you into a class on...
然后呢  在三个月之内学会吗
What? I'm gonna learn all this in three months?
你学习速度很快啊
You're a quick study!
你看你多快就学会魔术了
Look at how fast you learned magic.
我还有你小时候从你的尿布里拉出一条
I got a home movie of you pulling an impossibly long chain
超级无敌长的湿纸巾的影片呢
of baby wipes out of your diaper.
我五岁了还着穿尿布
Okay, I was 5 in a diaper.
那不能算作我学习速度快的证明吧
That's not really a sign of a quick learner.
我相信只要你愿意下功夫  你什么都能做到
I believe you can do anything you put your mind to.
为啥啊
Why?
我去
Oh! Shoot!
看来现在都是全自动化的了
I guess it's all computerized now.
那又怎样
Who cares?
靠  我真的超讨厌你这样
God, I hate it when you do this.
哪样啊  你看起来挺生气  你在生气吗
Do what? You look mad. Are you mad?
我跟你说过很多次了
...and I keep telling you,
可是感觉你从来没听进去
but it's like you're not hearing me!
真听不到  等等  先别说
I'm not. Wait, don't talk yet.
现在  快说
Go now, quick!
别再装作我不止如此
Stop acting like I'm someone I'm not!
别再我明明没那么好  却猛称赞我
Stop telling me how great I am when it's not true!
你看不出这样会给我造成很大压力吗
Don't you see how much pressure that is?!
卢克  不许你转身离我...
Luke, don't you walk away from --
而去
...me!
我可是你...
I'm your --
你怎么可能36岁啊
How are you 36?
脑子里一直在想你看起来超年轻
I just can't get over how young you look.
诀窍就是别笑太大
The trick is to not smile too hard.
你真有意思
You're funny.
我真没想到地震学家也能这么有趣
I did not expect that from a seismologist.
说到这里  你是怎么进入这行的啊
Which, by the way, how did you get into that?
天赋异禀  老天爷赏饭吃吧
Oh, um, it's just always come easy for me.
就是我只要扫一眼别人
You know? I look at people
很直觉就能知道她们的尺码
and I just instinctively know their size.
比如人家说"我衣服穿4号"
People are like, "Oh, I'm a 4,"
我就会说"少来了  胖妹
and I'm like, "Who you foolin', girl?
你穿10号"
You a 10."
女士  这是您要的纸巾
Ma'am, here is that napkin you asked for.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
哈哈  骗到你了吧
Ha ha. Fooled you.
刚才衣服的事情就是开玩笑
I was just joking about clothing stuff.
我真正开始学习地震的原因呢
The real reason why I got into studying earthquakes
是因为我热爱大自然
is because I love nature.
所以也难怪你对禽学也有兴趣了吧
I guess that would explain the ornithology interest, too, huh?
小姐  能再给我递张...
Miss, could I have another...
好啦  好啦  好啦
Um, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
天使一直都是超酷的东西嘛
Angels have always been cool,
但是再酷也没鸟类酷
but not as cool as birds!
我超爱鸟类
I love birds!
我爱我妈妈啊  真的
I mean, I love my mother, I do,
可是她这人自我中心  不考虑他人感受
but it's like her needs come before everyone else's.
你认识这样的人吗
You know that kind of person?
我好像真有认识呢
I think I do, yeah.
等等  为啥我开始聊起我妈了
Wait, why was I talking about her?
不知道啊  我本来是问
I don't know. The question was --
"你昨晚做什么了"
"What did you do last night?"
这问题我还在等你回答
And the question stands.
抱歉
Sorry.
我前夫
Ex-husband.
他就不能跟我儿子共处超过三小时
Honestly, it's like he can't be with my son
并且不问我一些没意义的愚蠢问题吗
for more than three hours without texting me some inane question.
原来你有个儿子啊
Oh -- Oh, you have a son?
我的一生挚爱
Love of my life.
离婚这事对他打击挺大
He took the divorce pretty hard.
他比较特别  你懂吗
He's...different, you know?
他比较...
He's really --
他很有创意  内心敏感
He's creative and sensitive,
在学校常常受欺负
and he gets picked on a lot at school.
真是幸好有他的舞蹈班
You know, it's like, thank God for his dance class.
感觉那里好像是唯一
I feel like it's the only place
我能看到他感到真正开心的地方
that I see, like, real joy on his face.
我就知道
I knew it.
你就是个大烂人
You're the worst!
你说什么
Excuse me?
我不是理查德  你个白痴
I'm not Richard, you fool.
我是被你跟你的大平板
I'm the father you and your giant iPad
夺走自己女儿初次芭蕾独舞的父亲
robbed of his daughter's first ballet solo.
我本来期望你有个
I hope whatever reason you had
很好的理由才把自己孩子放在我孩子之上
to prioritize your child over mine was a good one,
而现在我听到理由  虽然挺有理
and now that I hear it, it's pretty close,
这我承认  但你还是烂
I have to admit, but still.
你真是个神经病
You're a maniac,
但我挺庆幸的
but I'm grateful
因为这是我一生中所去过
because this has been one of the most abysmal dates
最烂的约会之一了
I have ever been on.
大多数人觉得猫咪都很冷淡
People think that cats are standoffish,
但我家的这只  每当我回家时...
but my guy, when I come home --
好了  我得请你暂停一下了
Okay, I've got to stop you right there.
我其实不是安娜  我们之间也不来电
I'm not Ana, and this isn't happening.
我感觉到了
I had a feeling.
我能起码跟你合个影吗
Can I at least take a picture with you
这样我能跟其他女人说我跟你约会过
so I can tell other women we dated?
什么  不行
What? No!
你说得对
You're right.
只是因为你真的超漂亮
It's just that you're so pretty.
好啦  过来拍一张吧
All right, get in here.
小姐
Ma'am?
曼尼  别这样
Manny, come on.
我们去派对要迟到了
We're going to be late for the mixer.
不好意思  我让你从冷板凳起来了吗
Excuse me, did I say your time-out was over?
回你床上去
Back on the bed.
对不起嘛  再也不整你了
I'm sorry, okay? No more pranks.
我发誓
I promise.
我就是想跟你玩一下嘛  真是的
I just wanted to have fun with you. Geez!
我忘了我在里面动了手脚
I forgot I did that one!
曼尼  对不起嘛
Aye, Manny! Por favor!
出去  你给我出去
Get out. Get out!
卢克  我们来谈谈
Luke, we should talk about this!
没什么好谈的
There's nothing to talk about.
你也别想来这个白痴的派对
And you're not coming to this stupid party.
-我要自己去  -我也是
- I'm going alone. - So am I.
我才不想去上什么傻逼钟琴课
Like I want to take some stupid bell class
只为了发掘另一个我不擅长的领域
so we can all find out there's one more thing I can't do.
别说了  至少你爸对你有信心
Oh, boo-hoo. Your dad believes in you.
我妈把我当日本整蛊节目的来宾一样
My mom's treating me like I'm on some Japanese game show.
好  你赢
Fine! You win!
比爸妈差劲你赢  比考大学你赢
You win worst parent, you win college.
祝你万事都赢  我就去地下铲屎处
Hope you have fun here while I'm shoveling poo
铲屎就好啦
in some underground poo-shoveling place.
如果你确信自己考不上
Well, why'd you even come here
为什么还要来呢
if you're so sure you can't get in?
我也不知道
I don't know.
大概这是唯一一个我们都能考上的地方
Maybe because this is the one place we might both get in.
和你一起  大学才不会那么可怕
That might make this whole thing a little less scary!
我也是因为这样才报名这里啊
Well, that's the only reason I applied, too!
-那我们还吵什么  -我哪知道
-Then why are we fighting?! -I don't know!
那我们还去派对吗
So, are we still going to the party?
去啊  等我戴个帽子
Yeah, I'll put on a hat!
我只想让卢克对自己有点自信
I just wanted Luke to feel good about himself, you know?
想给他加加油而已
Cheer him on a little.
大概过分鼓励也不好
Maybe there is such a thing as too much cheerleading.
如果你总是说有多相信他
You tell him he can do anything, and when he can't,
那他一旦失败  就会觉得令你失望了
he feels like he's disappointing you.
卢克知道我永远不会对他失望
Luke knows I'd never be disappointed in him.
是吗  卢克是很贴心
Does he? Luke is very sweet,
但也不是总那么灵光啊
but he doesn't know a lot of things.
所以我应该适当鼓励他
So I'm supposed to pump him up,
但不要过度鼓励以致他会担心令我失望
but not so much that he's afraid to let me down.
我做不好这件事也挺讽刺的
It's ironic that I'm struggling with this
因为我最厉害的拉拉队招式就是"穿针引线"
since my greatest cheerleading move was threading the needle.
就是7名拉拉队队员这么圈起手臂
It's when your seven cheermates make hoop arms --
不想听
I don't care.
我只想让曼尼能开得起玩笑
I just want Manny to learn how to take a joke.
但大喊"变态"然后把他
Yes, but there's a difference between a joke
他推进女更衣室还是跟
and yelling "Pervert!" before shoving him
普通开玩笑有差别的
into the girls' locker room.
多好玩啊
Aye, please, that was funny.
而且我这么挡着不让他出来时
Besides, I was the one who broke a heel
还把鞋跟弄坏了呢
trying to keep the door shut.
大学是人生中的重大改变
College is a big change.
我只想让他轻松应对
I'm just trying to keep it light for him.
是为了他还是为了你自己
For him or for you?
好啦
Okay.
这是他人生中第一次离开我
He's leaving me for the first time in his life.
我在婚姻中浮浮沉沉
I've been married, I've been divorced,
也曾不停搬家
I've lived here, I've lived there.
我开过出租车  也赢过"星探"节目
I drove a taxi, I won "Star Search."
可不管多少场变故  曼尼一直在我身边
Through all the changes in my life, there was always us.
像我的搭档
Like partners.
如果不保持搞笑的气氛  我会很难过的
If I don't keep this light, I am going to be very sad.
我知道  这不好受
I know. It stinks.
只能祈祷年底时  孩子会把你烦得不行
You just have to hope they get irritating enough
你就能开心地送他走了
by the end of the year that you're ready for them to go.
那我应该把口琴还给他
Maybe I should give him his harmonica back.
这么想就对了
That's the spirit.
你吃我这半块牛肉
Here, take my half steak.
我吃你半条鱼
I'll take half your fish.
我偶尔得骗骗我的动脉
I got to trick my arteries every once in a while,
不然他们又要造反了
keep them on their toes.
虽然我不知道你最近在忙什么
Well, I don't know what you're doing,
但你看上去很好
but you look great.
你气色也不错
And you look great, too.
吧台那里有个空位
Oh, look, there's no line at the bar.
看在往日情分去喝杯鸡尾酒如何
How about a Rob Roy for old time's sake?
中士  你还记得呢
Oh, you remembered, Sarge.
我怀孕的时候只喝这种酒
That was the only drink I could keep down when I was pregnant.
他们俩怎么了
Who are those people?
你听到了  他们是"中士"与"小豆宝"
You heard them. They're "Sarge" and "Pea."
我从没听他们这样称呼对方
Two nicknames I have never heard in my entire life.
我才不信他们俩能这么和谐
This kindness, I don't trust it.
-我懂  暴风雨前的宁静  -对
-I know, it's like a purple sky before a storm.  -Exactly.
美丽宁静  直到你发现鸟儿们惶恐不安
Beautiful, until you realize the birds are agitated
蚂蚁也围成了一个圈
and ants are walking in circles.
那什么
Actually, you know what?
我胃口不太舒服
My -- My stomach's feeling a little weird.
我得去走走  呼吸下新鲜空气
I think I'm gonna take a walk, get a little fresh air.
不准走
Oh, no. You don't --
这次我绝对不会让你跑了
You are not running away this time. No.
放开我  霸道鬼
Let go, bossy!
给我坐下  家人有罪一起受
Sit down. We are gonna suffer like a family!
别抓我  你别拉我的外套
No. Don't -- Don't stretch out my jacket!
我刚减肥到可以穿贴身版的
I just got back into slim fit!
-还好吗  -没事没事
-Is everything all right? -Yeah.
-他没事的  -我只是...
-He's fine. -I just --
是啊  亲爹如你  怎么会关心我呢
Oh, no, of course. Yeah, go get that.
这是怎么了
What's going on?
-没什么啦  -她推的我
-Oh... -She pushed me.
我没推他
I didn't push him.
他只是日常滑倒
He just, you know, slipped, fell.
坐下  你们俩怎么这么多戏
Sit down, sit down. You're causing a scene.
太丢人了
It's very embarrassing.
大小姐  你今天脾气很爆啊
You have been quite rude today, young lady.
跟巴顿将军有一拼
General Patton over there.
乔治·巴顿  二战著名美国军事统帅  性格强势
而你  就只会像布景一样傻坐着
And this one is basically a cardboard cutout
偶尔喝口酒  叹声气
who occasionally sip wine and sighs.
我们可没教育你们成为这样的人
We did not raise you to act like this.
-恕我直言  -让我来唱这个红脸
-Oh, excuse me. -No, I-I got it.
你们一直就是这样言传身教的好吗
No, in fact, you raised us to act exactly like this, okay?
你们俩才是今天发神经病的人
You two are the ones that are acting crazy.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
中士和小豆宝是谁啊
Who the hell are Sarge and Pea,
我们成长时怎么没见过这对神仙眷侣呢
and where were they when we were growing up?
如果是他们俩教养我们长大
Yeah, maybe if those two people had raised us,
那么家里也不会
there would have been room in our house
容不下有血有肉有感情的人
for other people to have emotions
某人就不用搞自闭  封闭感情了
and somebody wouldn't have had to shut himself down.
某人也不会总想着要
And maybe somebody wouldn't be trying
掌控全世界了
to control the whole world
全因为她长大的期间
because she couldn't control the chaos
她控制不了家中的混乱
in her own home growing up.
干嘛
Oh, come on.
我们谁不清楚她的问题在哪
We all know that's what's wrong with her.
-天  -所以
- Oh, God. - So, come on.
你们是不是还欠我们个解释
What do you have to say for yourselves?
-你说的一点没错  -我也承认
- Well, you're not wrong. - True.
-你说什么  -我没听错吧
- I'm -- I'm sorry. One more time. - What?
我们没离婚时  是做得不够好
We didn't behave well when we were married,
我也很内疚
and I feel bad about that.
我也是
Me too.
我们自以为硬不离婚是为了你们
We thought we were staying together for you,
但或许我们逼着你们
but I don't know, maybe we'd forced you
跟两个并不快乐的人相处了太久
to live with two unhappy people for too long.
但我们现在都很幸福
But we're happy now.
或许也因此  我们今天才能做最本来的自己
And that's probably why we're able to be our old selves today.
这些话我们早就该说
We should have said this a long time ago,
没能给你们一个快乐的童年
but we didn't give you the kind of home you deserved,
我们真的很抱歉
and for that, we're sorry.
你们不必这样
Well, you -- I mean, there was --
我们也有过幸福的时刻啊
There was happy times, too.
对啊  也不是一直都很疯癫
Yeah, no, it wasn't all crazytown.
-也有开心的时候  -是啊
- It was... - Yeah.
听
Listen.
话都说开了  我们能去跳舞了吗
We're good, right? We can go?
-去吧  -当然
Yes. Of course.
真没想到
Wow. How about that?
他们居然道歉了
An apology.
我从没想过我会如此释然
I don't think I ever thought it would feel so good.
看他们相亲相爱的样子我是很开心的
I do like seeing them happy.
是啊
Yeah.
别哭了
Ohh, you.
你闭嘴
Shut up.
我不像你是机器人
I feel stuff.
我懂啦
I know.
歌洛莉亚·迪尔加多
模特代言人
天呐  太牛了
Son of a bitch! That is coconuts!
我还记得你呢
I remember you!
你怀念当模特代言人的时光吗
Do you miss spokesmodeling?
我现在还偶尔做个帆船博览会呢
Aye, I do a boat show every now and then.
我是这么保持还在业界活动的
That's how I keep my hand in it.
快看
Watch, watch.
这是我的绝杀招数
This is how I sealed the deal.
又有一个你
It's you again.